<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>vpereira01</title><link>https://vpereira01.com/</link><description>vpereira01 site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vpereira01.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Upgrading my simple site with Cursor.AI</title><link>https://vpereira01.com/posts/site-upgrade-with-cursorai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vpereira01</author><guid>https://vpereira01.com/posts/site-upgrade-with-cursorai/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>I recently received an end-of-life notification for Bing Maps, with the recommended solution being to upgrade to Azure Maps. This affected my Electric Grid Power Outages site that I previously wrote about in another <a href="/posts/chatgpt-pt-power-outage/" rel="">post</a>. Additionally, I wanted to explore using E-Redes OpenData API to directly obtain power outage data rather than relying on third-party services.</p>
<h2 id="working-with-cursorai">Working with Cursor.AI</h2>
<p>My experience using Cursor.AI for this upgrade was a mixed bag:</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Creating a simple website using ChatGPT</title><link>https://vpereira01.com/posts/chatgpt-pt-power-outage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vpereira01</author><guid>https://vpereira01.com/posts/chatgpt-pt-power-outage/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Software development has too many paradigms, programming languages and tools to know it all. This sometimes makes me a bit frustrated since I known a lot about some languages and tools but creating a simple site can seem too much effort.</p>
<p>Now there&rsquo;s ChatGPT, without much effort or skill, here it&rsquo;s a site that shows Electric Grid Power Outages in Portugal <a href="https://vpereira01.com/electricalgridptqos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">https://vpereira01.com/electricalgridptqos/</a></p>
<p>I have wanted to create such site since I discovered that <a href="https://www.e-redes.pt/en/about-us" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">E-REDES</a>, the electrical power distributor, has an API that provides information about outages. Still, I always stopped when I thought the amount of stuff I would have to learn, debug and troubleshoot.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Why is Zoom help page broken? A router IPv6 bug</title><link>https://vpereira01.com/posts/zoom-ipv6-router-bug/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 10:48:54 +0100</pubDate><author>vpereira01</author><guid>https://vpereira01.com/posts/zoom-ipv6-router-bug/</guid><description>&lt;p>Trying to enable Zoom blur background in Linux I end up several times on the &lt;a href="https://support.zoom.us/hc/en-us/articles/360043484511" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Zoom Virtual Background system requirements&lt;/a> page which was always broken, as in, clicking on the Linux section did not expand to show the relevant information. It was annoying but I could reach the relevant information using the Firefox Web Developer Tools.
Nonetheless, it was bothering that it was always broken and if it was broken for everybody Zoom people would already handled it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Go big.Int add one performance curiosity</title><link>https://vpereira01.com/posts/go-bigint-perf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 15:15:11 +0100</pubDate><author>vpereira01</author><guid>https://vpereira01.com/posts/go-bigint-perf/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Trying to solve a coding exercise I noticed that doing <code>z.Add(z, one)</code> is kind of slow so I implemented my own increment method :)</p>
<p>Practicing Go by solving the CodeWars <a href="https://www.codewars.com//kata/54cb771c9b30e8b5250011d4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">exercise</a> &ldquo;Fabergé Easter Eggs crush test&rdquo;, I was able to find a simple, and slow solution, by performing many many additions. This simple solution was enough to meet the test requirements but something bugged me from my CPU profilings, <code>z.Add(z, one)</code> was taking cumulative more than one second. In comparison, adding two big numbers was taking cumulative more than five seconds.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Hi and site setup</title><link>https://vpereira01.com/posts/hey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 15:59:34 +0100</pubDate><author>vpereira01</author><guid>https://vpereira01.com/posts/hey/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="hi-and-welcome-to-my-site-">Hi and welcome to my site :)</h1>
<p>For a while I thought it was a good idea to set up a personal site, or blog, but like others I had always postponed it.
Recently because I lived through an interesting tech story I finally decided to do it.</p>
<p>Since this is my first site/blog please excuse my lacking writing skills.</p>
<h2 id="choosing-a-domain-and-registrar">Choosing a domain and registrar</h2>
<p>My GitHub username has ended up being my handle/nick on most professional and tech platforms so reusing it seemed like a good option.
Having the &ldquo;01&rdquo; on &ldquo;vpereira01&rdquo; does not sound great but it&rsquo;s preferable to have a recognizable name than to try to find a better domain.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>